Item 4 is public input and unscheduled personal appearances in the audience, which is to address the special utility authority on any of the agenda items.
There are being nine item five as a consent agenda staff is recommending item six and seven, which are claims and minutes for the consent agenda.
If there are no questions on those items, I'll entertain a motion to approve.
And a second.
Say roll call.
Item 8 is consider and adopt the resolution authorizing the sale issuance and delivery of certificates of indebtedness.
With the authority to provide funds for capital improvements authorizing sale.
The discount and waving the credit of bidding.
They're on Greg Mito.
Hey Greg.
We want to come up and if you and Dean want to tag team on this.
Well, as you know, our wild and financial.
Study and the new.
Ordin are the new rates that we've had for our electric rates indicated that we would have a fairly substantial bond issue primarily for.
Two of our substations rebuilding those and also some work in our electrical utilities.
In fact, the next item will be talking about some work in one of our substations.
So as we have our agreement with Greg Greg has come up with alternatives related to.
The issuance of about eight million dollars in debt that was identified by the world and that we have the capacity to do.
And we do have a recommendation for you and I'll let Greg go ahead and cover that.
I'd like to just bring you up.
Jill just passed out some information.
We did some studies and back into the numbers.
It looked at eight million dollar bond issue, which apparently will meet your days for the electric improvements.
And that will net you approximately $7,680,000 dollars.
You can see on that one sheet.
What that does, it allows us to take care of what the rate increases.
But your average debt service is about $675,000 dollars per year.
And one thing to keep in mind, this is based on today's interest rates.
As you all know what has happened, the interest rates are the last several months.
We want to look at this and try to work together when you want to actually go into debt.
And then when you want to start making payments, but also lock it in the rate, it's an extra-diciously possible.
What this resolution authorizes is not to exceed figures.
We will issue the $8 million in the net.
Even though the resolution says more than that, we will still issue the $8 million.
It also has a state interest rate.
That's not to exceed figures.
But you can see we're well.
We feel right now we're well below that.
It should be 23 and 4% on the average rate.
It will be a fixed rate.
But also on the cost of this market, things can change so dramatically.